# Alberto Sonnino

https://sonnino.com

### Personal Data

PLACE & DATE OF BIRTH: Brussels, Belgium | 12 February 1992

LOCATION: London, United Kingdom

Phone and Email: +44 20 7679 0293 | alberto.sonnino@ucl.ac.uk

### Interests

I was a co-founder and researcher at Chainspace, which builds a scalable smart contract platform; I am now a Research Scientist at the Blockchain team of Facebook based in London.

My main research interests are in privacy enhancing technologies, distributed ledgers, and cryptography. I have a special interest in trusted hardware and FPGA-based security applications. In the past, I worked on numerical calculations and simulations for physics-related problems (plasma physics, category theory, symmetry groups).

#### EXPERIENCES

2019 -	Research Scientist, Facebook, London (United Kingdom). Blockchain Team.
2018 - 2019	Co-Founder and Researcher, Chainspace, Gibraltar. Building a scalable decentralised smart contacts platform.
2017 -	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , University College London, London (United Kingdom). Introduction to Computer Science, Introduction to Security.
2008 - 2017	Private Teacher, London (United Kingdom).  Mathematics, chemistry, physics, electricity/electronics, and computer science.
2016 - 2017	Internal Security, Smals, Brussels (Belgium).  National cybersecurity – focus on protection of social and health care data.
2013 - 2014	Coach and Trainer, Catholic University of Louvain, Louvain-La-Neuve (Belgium). University water-polo team, winner of the National Inter-University Tournament 2013-2014.
2008 - 2011	Water-Polo Player, Royal Brussel Poseidon, Brussels (Belgium).  Member of the water-polo team ROYAL BRUSSEL POSEIDON, 1 <sup>st</sup> National League.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 -	University College London (UCL), London, United Kingdom. Ph.D, Security Engineering.
2015 - 2016	University College London (UCL), London, United Kingdom. Master Degree, Information Security.
2013 - 2015	Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Karlsruhe, Germany.  Master Degree, Elektrotechnik und Informationstechnik.
2013 - 2015	Catholic University of Louvain (UCLouvain), Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium.  Master Degree, Electrical Engineering.
2010 - 2013	Catholic University of Louvain (UCLouvain), Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium. Bachelor Degree, Engineering.

## LANGUAGES

FRENCH: Native ENGLISH: Fluent DUTCH: Scolar Level ITALIAN: Native GERMAN: Intermediate SPANISH: Basic Knowledge

## REFERENCES

Available on demand.